GPT 5.4 Mini and Nano were just released
and for the first time ever it's called
out in the headline for these models
that they are built for sub-agents,
especially for AI coding. And this is
more important than you would think. I
mean, yes, these are fantastic models
and we'll talk about that as well. But
what's more important here is the
message from OpenAI. They are putting a
lot of effort into designing LLMs that
are specifically meant to be used for
sub-agents. And sub-agents are just a
big deal right now in general. There's a
lot happening with them in the industry.
Claude Code is building a lot around
sub-agents. We also have Google that
just released Gemini 3.1 Flash Light
built for intelligence at scale.
Recently, there's been more focus on
building the smaller models than the
larger, most powerful ones and that says
something. That's why I'm saying we're
going into the sub-agent era. And so, I
want to talk about what that means for
you and just share with you how I'm
using sub-agents right now because I'm
using them for literally everything. All
of my research, all of my AI coding
workflows. Now, for the longest time
Claude Haiku 4.5 has been my model of
choice. Whenever I want something
extremely cheap and fast for my
sub-agent usage cuz I'm using sub-agents
all the time for web research and code
base analysis. We'll talk about that in
a little bit as well. But for a very
cheap model, it's still not that fast.
53 tokens per second is pretty good, but
we're still paying $1 for every 1
million input tokens and $5 for every 1
million output tokens. So, it's still
not extremely cheap. And so, now we have
GPT 5.4 Nano and Mini. Even Nano is more
powerful than Claude Haiku 4.5 and it is
a fifth of the price. And look at the
throughput here, 188 tokens per second
according to the 5.4 Nano listing on
OpenRouter. And even 5.4 Mini is cheaper
than Claude Haiku. Also very, very fast.
This is way more powerful than Claude
Haiku 4.5. And so, I'm literally
thinking I might want to switch to Codex
from Claude Code because of how much I
love using sub-agents. Now, I know
benchmarks aren't everything, but let me
quickly show you why I'm saying these
models are a lot better than Haiku 4.5.
So, the benchmarks right from OpenAI say
that 5.4 Mini and Nano, they actually
crush the predecessor, GPT-5 Mini. But,
if we look at Live Bench, GPT-5 Mini has
a global average score across the
benchmarks of about 66. And then,
looking at Claude Haiku 4.5, it's only
61. So, Live Bench doesn't have 5.4 Mini
and Nano yet, but even looking at the
predecessor, that even is still better
than Claude Haiku 4.5. And so, we're
seeing these cheaper and faster models
that are also getting way better at the
same time. But, let me also be very
clear here. The point of this video is
to not just shill the new OpenAI models.
Yeah, they're cool, but I want to focus
on the trajectory here. Especially with
competition, we're going to keep seeing
all of these smaller models being built
that are faster, cheaper, and still
really powerful. And if we keep this up,
we're eventually going to get to the
point where we pretty much have an
unlimited budget for sub-agent usage.
And that's going to unlock so much for
us to solve a lot of these problems
around context rot. Let's talk about
that right now. So, the simple idea
behind context rot is large language
models get overwhelmed with information
just like people do. Just because your
Claude Code, Codex, whatever can support
1 million tokens doesn't mean you should
overload it with that much information.
We see a general decline no matter the
large language model as we load it with
more context. So, there's more
hallucinations, it picks out specific
information we need it less often. This
is a real problem. There's a lot of
solutions to context rot. I actually
covered it in my last video that I'll
link to right here with the whisk
framework. And one of the most important
things that I covered there is isolation
with sub-agents. If we want to keep our
main context clean so our main agent can
be very focused, especially during AI
coding sessions. One of the most
important strategies is to delegate a
bunch of code base analysis or web
research to sub agents. These are the
two uses of sub agents that I'm relying
on every single day, pretty much every
single AI coding workflow. Because we
can have it do tens or even hundreds of
thousands of tokens of research, and
then just provide the context that we
really need to our main agent. So we can
extend our coding agent with all these
arms of sub agents doing different
context gathering, but then still
keeping our main agent very focused. And
this is becoming more and more plausible
to do an insane amount of code base
analysis and web research because these
LLMs that we can use to power our sub
agents are getting cheaper and better
and faster. Now, the reason we care so
much about using these faster and
cheaper models for sub agents is because
the work that we're delegating to the
sub agents are the kind of thing that
are super token heavy, but also don't
require as much reasoning power. So it's
overkill to use something like
GPT-5.4-High
or Claude-Opus-4.6.
If we use those larger models for sub
agents, where we're doing hundreds of
thousands of tokens of code base
research and web research, you're going
to hit your rate limit for your coding
agent very, very quickly. But if
[snorts] you're using these faster
models that are so dirt cheap
comparatively, your sub agent usage is
only going to make up a couple of
percent of your total rate limit for the
week. And so we need this efficiency
because with these cheaper and faster
models, the scale is incredible for what
we can do with sub agents, and it's only
getting better and better. That's why
the industry is leaning so much into sub
agents right now, and all these tools
are building a ton of support around
them. Claude Code was the first coding
agent to introduce sub agents, but even
they have had a lot of recent changes,
adding support for building custom hooks
for sub-agent. Their documentation just
grows every single day with what they're
building into sub-agents. We got them in
Codex, obviously, as well. This is where
you can use GPT-5.4 Mini. And then it's
experimental in the Gemini CLI. It was
added to GitHub Copilot recently for
research, code analysis, code review. A
lot of these coding agents have
sub-agents built directly in, so you
don't even have to create custom ones
anymore, either, for most things. We
have it in Cursor. Of course, we have it
in Open Code, as well. The point is
every single coding agent and large
language model provider is focusing so
much on sub-agents right now. Okay, so
with that, I want to give you one big
word of warning for using sub-agents.
Then we'll get into exactly how I use
them every single day, so you can walk
away with some immediate wins. So,
there's a video I put out on my channel
recently covering this diagram. I'll
link to that video right here. This is
just my entire AI coding workflow that
I'm using every single day. And
obviously, sub-agents for context
isolation and research is a big part of
that. So, like I said earlier, code base
analysis and validation and web
research, but only those things. My word
of warning is do not try to use
sub-agents for implementation. It
doesn't work. I only use it for research
because we are spending tens or hundreds
of thousands of tokens analyzing things
and only returning a small summary to
our main agent. That works well for
research when we're just trying to
synthesize a bunch of information. But
for implementation, our main agent needs
to be aware of all of the files that
we're changing, otherwise it has no way
to validate. There's a lot of
hallucinations that have happened here
in my experience. I've tried to use
sub-agents where I have my front-end
sub-agent, my back-end sub-agent, my
database sub-agent. They all work in
parallel, but they're not talking to
each other. They're not giving the main
agent everything that it needs, and so
there's a lot of problems that come with
this. So, stick to your main agent for
your implementation, but then at the
start of your coding session when you're
just going through the planning, that is
when I recommend using sub agents a ton.
And so, with that, let's get into how I
use sub agents every single day. All
right, I got a super quick interruption
because I built my own agentic rag agent
with a new database I've never used
before that I'm super excited to show
you. The sponsor of today's video is
Oracle, and I'm excited for this one
because of how they're approaching AI
infrastructure with their AI database.
So, if you've ever built any rag system
or AI agent before, you know that your
architecture looks something like this.
You have the main database for your app,
and then usually you'll have a separate
vector database, maybe even a separate
graph database. You have your embedding
API and the pipeline to sync everything
together. That's how it's always been
done, but it's not easy to manage all of
that. And with Oracle's AI database,
everything is a unified. So, you have
the embeddings built right into the
database, and you can do your semantic
keyword and even knowledge graph search
all in one place. I've never seen
something like this before. I even have
my own agentic rag system that I created
on top of the Oracle AI database that I
have packaged up into this Jupiter
notebook that I'll link to in the
description. And so, really quick, it
just loads sample documents. I demo some
of the different search strategies that
are native to the database, and then I
create a LangChain and LangGraph agents.
I'll show you this right now. I'll run a
demo here where we send in some queries,
and we can watch it perform the
different search strategies in the
Oracle AI database, come back with the
relevant documentation to then give us
our final answer. And Oracle has an
open-source AI developer hub, giving you
a bunch of resources to leverage their
platforms like their AI database. And I
actually submitted a pull request for
this Jupiter notebook. It got approved,
so I'll have a link to this in the
description. Like I said, you can go and
run the whole thing yourself. All right,
so I'm here now in my cloud code, and
I'll obviously show codex as well
because that's where you can use the new
5.4 models. So, whenever I am starting a
brand new AI coding session to knock out
a feature or a bug fix, I always start
with my prime command. So, no sub agents
yet. I want to load a high-level
overview of the project into the context
of my main coding agent. That's the
workflow that I walk through right here.
But now, at this point, our main Claude
code instance is loaded up with context.
Now, I want to use sub agents very
extensively. I'll do this every single
time. When I'm working with larger code
bases, there's a lot of context to sift
through to figure out what parts of the
code base do we really care about
addressing for this feature or bug fix.
And so, for brand new projects or simple
projects, you don't really care about
sub agents. There's not really going to
be a problem of context rot. But I'm
working in my Archon code base. More on
this coming on my channel soon, by the
way. But the point here is it's a very
complicated code base. I have a ton of
different packages. There's tens of
thousands of lines of code. I don't want
to just dive right in and say like,
"Hey, look at my code base and try to
find the right files to address this
feature." I want to use sub agents cuz I
need that context isolation. So, I'll
give you kind of a random example here,
but like a real example. I hope this
helps drive the home the point for you
here. So, I'll go into my speech-to-text
tool and I'll say, "I want to address a
bug here." So, the issue I'm running
into right now is whenever I start
multiple workflows in the same
conversation, they share the same work
tree. So, I want you to help me plan
this fix by spinning up three
exploratory sub agents. One to search
the web for best practices for handling
work trees with these AI coding workflow
execution tools. Another one to research
the web adapter and see how the bug
applies there. And then another sub
agent to research the back end and see
how we are managing work trees with
conversations.
So, there we go. I'll send this off, and
And isn't even using any sub agents that
I've built for myself. Like I said, a
lot of these tools are implementing sub
agents directly into the platform, so we
can use them out of the box without
having to define anything. And these
built-in sub agents are smart enough to
use faster and cheaper models under the
hood. So, when we invoke the web
researcher, and then the other sub
agents that we'll see in a second here,
like our code base analysts, these are
again both sub agents built into Claude
code, they are using either Haiku or
Sonnet under the hood instead of Opus,
which is the model that my main context
window is working in. So, a clear
example here of working with different
models depending on if we're in our main
session or if we're in a sub agent. And
we can do the exact same thing with
Codex. And so, I'll just do the same
prompt here.
I have a bug right now where work trees
are shared when I'm invoking many
workflows in the same chat. So, spin up
three sub agents, one to do web research
on best practices around work tree
management, one to look into this bug as
it relates to the web adapter, and then
one to look into the back end. So, doing
just a bit of a shorter prompt here for
the sake of example, but then what I can
also do is say, "I want you to use
GPT-5.4
Mini for these sub agents so they can be
faster and cheaper." We want to be more
context efficient here. And so, we'll
see in just a second when Codex spins up
these sub agents, it'll explicitly tell
us that they are using the new GPT-5.4
Mini model. And this is so incredibly
fast. It's really cool to see. So, there
we go. It spawned three sub agents, and
each one of them is using GPT-5.4 Mini
with medium reasoning. We don't need
that much reasoning here because all
we're doing is synthesizing information.
And I know this is a pretty basic
example overall, but you can spin up
dozens of sub agents in parallel. A lot
of times when you're working on very
large code bases or projects that have
many code bases, there's so much context
curation you have to do to really
identify the problem for a bug fix or
exactly where you need to implement a
new feature. Running code reviews as
well is another really good use of
sub-agents. There's so many times where
I'm just relying on sub-agents very,
very deeply. Like I wouldn't be able to
work without them. So, take a look at
this. All of our sub-agents are done
across both coding agents. For Claude
code, we used 80,000, 96,000, and 40,000
tokens across the three sub-agents. And
then for Codex, it's even crazier. We
used 70,000 for our research into the
front-end. And then we used almost 2
million tokens for our web research and
almost 1 and 1/2 million for our
back-end research. This would be
completely unreasonable if we were using
larger models. But thanks to these super
cheap models that are still pretty
powerful, we can extend the arms of our
coding agent this much to help work with
larger code bases. And by the way, for
Claude code, we can specify the model.
Like we can tell it to use Haiku for the
sub-agent or use Sonnet for the
sub-agent, just like we did here in
Codex. So, a lot of flexibility, a lot
of control here. I'm using sub-agents
for everything. That's where the
industry is heading going into the
sub-agent era. So, my encouragement to
you is to just try using sub-agents for
literally everything, not just the
planning process. Another random example
that's super useful is sometimes when
I'm working on a feature, I'll find an
unrelated bug. And so, I'll just spin up
a sub-agent to research that bug and
create a GitHub issue. So, it's sort of
like a sidecar, so I'm not polluting my
primary work. There are a million uses
for sub-agents, and it's just going to
get cheaper and faster and better over
time. And so, if you appreciated this
video and you're looking forward to more
things on AI coding and using
sub-agents, I would really appreciate a
like and a subscribe. And with that, I
will see you in the next video.